<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teachings on gragusa.org</title>
    <link>https://gragusa.org/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Teachings on gragusa.org</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gragusa.org/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduzione all&#39;Econometria</title>
      <link>https://gragusa.org/teaching/intrometrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gragusa.org/teaching/intrometrics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The course name says it all: introduction to econometrics taught in italian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;L’obiettivo del corso è di introdurre gli studenti all’econometria
usando un approccio prevalentemente applicato. Sebbene sono trattati sia gli aspetti
teorici che quelli pratici, l’accento è posto sulla comprensione intuitiva dei concetti
chiave delle tecniche econometriche che sono illustrati con applicazioni empiriche aventi ad oggetto
questioni economiche rilevanti nel dibattito di policy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Econometrics</title>
      <link>https://gragusa.org/teaching/tsmetrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gragusa.org/teaching/tsmetrics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time Series Econometrics is aimed at students who wish to gain a working knowledge of the modern methods used in macroeconomics and to some extent in finance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of the course, students will have gained a good understanding of time series econometrics ranging from classic tools such as linear stationary processes (ARMA, VAR) to techniques that have recently entered the macroeconomist toolbox (Bayesian and high dimensional estimation).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Econometrics</title>
      <link>https://gragusa.org/teaching/advmetrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gragusa.org/teaching/advmetrics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This course gives a thorough coverage of classical econometric theory with an
emphasis on the estimation of causal relations between economic variables.
Applications in the areas of microeconomics and macroeconomics will be
considered.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Econometrics of DSGE models</title>
      <link>https://gragusa.org/teaching/eief-dsge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gragusa.org/teaching/eief-dsge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a course on the econometric techniques used in the estimation of dynamic
macroeconomic models (DSGE models). The aim of the course is mostly theoretical, but applications are also presented using &lt;a href=&#34;http://julialang.org&#34;&gt;Julia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applied Econometrics and Statistics</title>
      <link>https://gragusa.org/teaching/ase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gragusa.org/teaching/ase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The aim of this course is to provide an introduction to the practice of
econometrics. While both theoretical and practical aspects will be covered,
emphasis will be on intuitive understanding. Concepts will be illustrated with
real world applications on real world data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Econometric Theory</title>
      <link>https://gragusa.org/teaching/grad-et/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gragusa.org/teaching/grad-et/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The course main objective is to provide students with a solid grasp of the
probabilistic and statistical underpinnings of the most common econometric
techniques. The topics studied will be of practical use to any student who plans
on confronting data in their thesis or wishes to read and precisely understand
the econometrics typically used in empirical research published in academic
journals. The recommended software package is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.julialang.org&#34;&gt;Julia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Econometrics Review Course</title>
      <link>https://gragusa.org/teaching/eief-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gragusa.org/teaching/eief-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Econometric Review Course is a 20 hours long course. I am teaching half of the
course; the other half is taught by Marco Lippi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my part I will focus on the specification and estimation of the linear
regression model. The course departs from the standard Gauss-Markov assumptions
to include heteroskedasticity, serial correlation, and errors in variables.
Advanced topics include generalized least squares, instrumental variables,
generalized method of moments, limited dependent variable models, and panel
data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://gragusa.org/teaching/lbs-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gragusa.org/teaching/lbs-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This course gives an overview of many techniques, and algorithms in machine learning, beginning with topics such as linear regression and classification and ending up with more recent topics such as boosting, support vector machines, random forests and and unsupervised learning techniques. The course will give the student the ideas and intuition behind modern machine learning methods as well as a bit more formal understanding of how, why, and when they work. The module will use primarily the &lt;a href=&#34;http://r-project.org&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; programming language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>